MICHAEL FRABOTT

MICHAEL.FRABOTT@GMAIL.COM • (614) 306-3071 • WESTERVILLE, OHIO

GITHUB: github.com/mfrabott

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/michael-frabott
PORTFOLIO: mfrabott.github.io/frabott-portfolio

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: React, Express, Node, Handlebars, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

GRAPHICAL RESERVATION

Working in a team of four, we set out to build a proof-of-concept application allowing users to make a reservation for a specific table at their restaurant of choice using Handlebars, Express, and MySQL. My primary contributions included database architecture, establishment of server routes, handling session data, and implementing the dynamic floorplan functionality.

Repository: <u>github.com/afredknot/Table-Reservation</u> Live Application: <u>graphical-restaurant.herokuapp.com/</u>

MORE THAN A GAME

Tasked with incorporating third-party APIs into a novel concept, my team built an application allowing users to search for a college football team's schedule, choose a game from the results, and populate a list of local attractions and other events taking place during the weekend of the chosen game through a series of cascading fetch calls. I lead the JavaScript development, including API calls and data parsing.

Repository: <u>github.com/mfrabott/More-Than-A-Game</u> Live Application: <u>mfrabott.github.io/More-Than-A-Game/</u>

SUMMARY

After enjoying a successful career working as a paralegal, I recently decided to embark on a new challenge to become a web developer. While my role and responsibilities in my recent position continued to expand, I realized that I wanted to spend more time focusing on the aspects of my job that I enjoyed and excelled at the most - working through technical questions and logic problems and expanding on opportunities to be more creative. With a skill set directly transferable from my legal background and the foundation I have worked to build in Ohio State University's Full-Stack Program, I have already found web development to be a great personal fit early on in my new career trajectory.

Dealing primarily with oil and gas matters, I have assisted hundreds of landowners in the negotiation of comprehensive leases and easement agreements and helped develop and implement winning strategies in complex litigation in state, federal, and appellate courts. Most recently, I oversaw the management of a putative class-action trespass case with over 1,000 members and encompassing roughly 30,000 acres of affected land.

I look forward to bringing my attention to detail, eagerness to learn, and ability to balance independent work and collaboration to a new environment where I can both push myself and contribute to the development of innovative and useful applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

C.J. Wilson Law, LLC Paralegal

Columbus, OH May 2017-October 2022

- Managed a putative federal class action mineral trespass case of roughly 30,000 acres with over one million pages of discovery documents
- Oversaw final editing and proofreading of all legal briefs
- Developed and implemented winning strategies in heavily contested lawsuits
- Completed title abstracting and drafted purchase agreements, deeds, oil & gas leases, and easement agreements
- Resolved mineral ownership and lease termination disputes through lawsuits and settlement negotiations
- Managed case schedules in trial, appellate, federal, and administrative cases
- Identified potential clients and established marketing campaigns

Emens & Wolper Law Firm, LPA Paralegal Columbus, OH October 2014 – May 2017

- Responsible for overseeing 450+ landowner-client relationships across four natural gas pipeline projects
- Heavily involved in negotiating, drafting, and facilitating the execution of pipeline easements and oil & gas leases
- Organized, marketed, and hosted educational seminars for landowners
- Maintained estate, trust, and LLC bylaws, resolutions, minutes, and other records

Cameron Mitchell Restaurants Lead Trainer, Sales Associate, Human Resources Intern Columbus, OH; Indianapolis, IN June 2009 – May 2016

- Asserted a leadership role in assisting and training new and existing associates
- Worked in casual and fine-dining restaurants to cater to the expectations of thousands of guests
- Chosen to assist in introducing and establishing the company brand into a new market
- Created, organized, and maintained personnel files as an intern
- Processed new employee forms, unemployment cases, benefits claims, and conducted internal audits

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate The Ohio State University January 2022 ABA Paralegal Certificate Capital University Law School August 2014 Bachelor of Arts, Sociology and Criminology The Ohio State University December 2011